(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T00:01:19.899764",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ロボ子さん
Robocosan
IRyS
一伊那尓栖
Ninomae Ina'nis
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
轟はじめ
Todoroki Hajime
ラプラス・ダークネス
La+ Darknesss
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
????
Oh!
Up we go.
Yeah, let's go!
Hehehe!
Huh?
Mmm...
What the bleh?!
Ah, ah, ah!
Ahhhhh!
Whoaaaa!
Whoa! Ow!
Ow, ow, ow...
Dang it! Ow...
Ah, my head... Ah...
What's going on?
Where... Where am I?
No way! Did I get sucked into the game world?!
What... What do I do?
Hello?
Hello?!
Why are there so many eyes on me?
Hello?
Hello?!
They're not saying anything.
Oh, I have to get back!
Today is such an important day, I can't get stuck in here!
Uh, what should I do?
I guess I have to figure this out on my own. Um...
So many people looking at me. Are those Pebbles? Hello!
Are you expecting me to do something?
Maybe I should sing and dance, cuz this looks like a stage?
Maybe...?
Maybe that'll be how I get out.
Okay. Okay, I got it then.
I'm going to sing and dance a song right now!
Here we go!
This game!
回り続ける 歯車には
To a gear that keeps rotating...
成り下がらない
...I will never degrade myself.
平均演じる
Playing the average role,
誕生から始まった地獄
a hell that started from my birth.
遊び半分で 神が導いた
With halfhearted play, God guided us...
盤上の世界
...to this world on a game board.
no no no game no life
ぬるい平穏を ばっさり切り捨てて
Drastically cutting away lukewarm peace,
栄光への階段に 存在刻むんだ
I will carve my existence onto the stairs of glory!
目に映るのは
What is reflected in my eyes...
完全勝利の運命
...is the fate of complete victory.
何もかも 計算どおり
Everything is just as calculated.
変えてやる 染まらない空白で
I will change it, with this un-stainable blank space!
We are maverick
救済なんていらない
We don't need any salvation.
どんな不条理 襲おうとも
No matter what absurdity attacks us,
勝てばいいだけの話だろう<,s:
all we have to do is win, right?
駆け引きと 才能が
Bargaining and talent...
無敗誘う
...invite us to invincibility.
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
We'll enjoy ourselves with this reborn life!
自分だけは 自分信じてる
At least we will believe in ourselves.
心に潜む闇より
Than the darkness lurking in our hearts,
強い相手はいない
there is no opponent stronger.
挫けぬ限り そこに<,s:
As long as we don't falter,
敗敗は あり得ない
defeat is impossible there.
上辺の個性で 安心と引き換えに プライド殺すな
Don't kill your pride with superficial individuality in exchange for security!
no no no sence of life
No, no, no sense of life.
野蛮な雑音を きっぱり蹴飛ばして<,s:
Completely kicking away the savage noise,
誰より純粋な 声上げるんだ
I will raise a voice purer than anyone else's!
戦うことは
Fighting...
きっと間違いじゃない
...is surely not a mistake.
手応えが 教えてくれた
The feedback has told us so.
全て失っても 勝ち残れ
Even if we lose everything, survive and win!
We are maverick
常識なんていらない
We don't need any common sense.
前へならえ 向かう先に
If we just fall in line, what lies ahead...
待ってるのは退屈だろう
...is surely boredom.
言いなりじゃ つまらない
Just doing as told is boring.
挑んでやる
I will challenge it!
生まれ直した命も
Using even our reborn lives...
駒にして
...as chess pieces,
自分だけの道を 最後まで
we'll walk our own path until the very end.
迷わない 選ばれし者
We won't hesitate, for we are the chosen ones.
真っ赤なうぬぼれでも
Even if it's just pure conceit,
誇らしく生き抜くための方法を
the way to survive with pride...
一つしか知らないから
...is the only one we know!
We are maverick
救済なんていらない
We don't need any salvation.
どんな不条理 襲おうとも
No matter what absurdity attacks us,
勝てばいいだけの話だろう
all we have to do is win, right?
駆け引きと 才能が
Bargaining and talent...
無敗誘う
...invite us to invincibility.
生まれ直した命で 楽しむさ
We'll enjoy ourselves with this reborn life!
この世界 手にして 笑うんだ
We will take this world in our hands and laugh!
We are maverick
最強の maverick gamers
the strongest maverick gamers.
空白ならば 何者にもなれる
Since we are a blank space, we can become anything.
自分だけは 自分信じてる
At least we will believe in ourselves.
Yeah! How was that? That was the best performance ever, right?
Hey! Over there! You liked it, right? Hey!
With this, I should be able to get back to my own world.
All right, I'm ready. Beam me up, Pebbles!
Ah... Ah!
What? Why is it shaking? Why is it shaking?!
No! My coins! Where are you going?
Well, according to video game logic, this must mean I must now go on an epic quest to find the coins or something.
But I don't have time for that! I need the coins back to get home! No!
Huh? Huh? Oh, what's this?
Uh, I mean, I came out through there, so maybe this will take me, you know, on my next step of my quest?
Well, better than being stuck here. So...
Let's go!
Ah!
Oof... I'm not back in my world?
ここどこ？
Where is this?
待っていたよ、ビブー
I've been waiting for you, Biboo.
[Robocosan Joins the Battle! Fighting Game Battle]
え？え？ロボ子先輩？
Eh? Eh? Roboco-senpai?
探しているのは... これ？
Is this... what you're looking for?
あ！コイン！コイン！
Ah! The coin! The coin!
これがないと元の世界に戻れないんですよ！
Without this, I can't return to my original world!
でもそうはさせない。ゲームマスターである僕たちから、すべて取り戻せるかな？
But I won't let you do that. Can you win them all back from us, the game masters?
え？本当？入るの？あれ？え？あ？
Eh? Really? A battle? Uh, wait...
とにかく、このコインが欲しければ、僕と勝負だ！
Anyway, if you want this coin, battle me!
勝負？！
A match?!
そう、イエス！格闘ゲームで勝負だ！
Yes, indeed! A battle in a fighting game!
うーん、よし、負けないぞ！
Mmm, alright, I won't lose!
うわ！のー！
Whoa! No!
L & UP B
L R Dash & B
L R STOP & Dash & TALK B B A B S
これが私をリモートコントロールする機械です
This is the machine that remote controls me
少し歪な形しておりますが、使えます
It has a somewhat distorted shape, but it works
Yeah!
UP SIDE DOWN A B A B B A B A 左右
UP SIDE DOWN A B A B B A B A Left, Right
L R L R STOP & Dash & UP & TALK 異常ナシ
L R L R STOP & Dash & UP & TALK No abnormalities
L R L R STOP & Dash & UP & TALK
もうちっとで外に出られるののにあ
Just a little bit more and I could get outside
どうやってもうまくいかね
No matter what I do, it doesn't go well
まだまだ足りない
Still, still not enough!
座る 座る sit down please
Sit, sit, sit down please
フィードバックに体預けて
Entrusting my body to feedback
巡る 巡る turn it around
Spinning, spinning, turn it around
うなりを上げて、モーター状態
Raising a roar, motor state
踊る 踊る dancin' night
Dancing, dancing, dancin' night
マッシュアップでもれなくアガる
Rising without exception in a mashup
声をあげて singin' now
Raising your voice, singin' now
あの子よりも上手く歌いたい
I want to sing better than that girl
これがボクをリモートで操縦できる機械です
This is the machine that can remote pilot me
説明書は紛失しておりますが使えます
Although the manual is lost, it works
UP SIDE DOWN A B A B B A B A 右左
Up side down A B A B B A B A Right, Left
L R L R STOP & Dash & UP & TALK 異常ナシ
L R L R STOP & Dash & UP & TALK No abnormalities
L R L R STOP & Dash & UP & TALK
からかってるみたいな いつもの顔
You have that same teasing face as always,
（余裕でしょ？）
("You got this, right?")
今日はかなり本気だぜ？
I'm pretty serious today, you know?
ほら、すぐキメるぜ！
Look, I'll finish this in no time!
座る 座る (oh) sit down please
Sit, sit, (oh) sit down please
トークバックを頭に挿して
Plugging the talkback into my head,
回る 回る (oh) turn it around
Spin, spin, (oh) turn it around
ちょっと待って、スタンバイ状態
Hold on a second, I'm on standby.
踊る 踊る (oh) dancin' night
Dance, dance, (oh) dancin' night
ジャストフィットなリズムを出してうなり上げる
Creating a perfect-fit rhythm, making it roar!
singin' now
あいつよりも高くうたいたい
I want to sing higher than them.
ほれたはれたのなないろさむらい
Infatuated with love, a seven-colored samurai,
あらいざらいしゅちょうするそんざい
An existence that lays everything bare,
おもいちがいがすけてるあんばい
A state where misunderstandings show through,
こわいくらいのわくてかじょうたい
An almost frighteningly excited state!
きにしないのがあなたの policy
Not caring about it is your policy,
なやんでいてもおなかはへるし
Even when worrying, you still get hungry.
なんだかんだでせけんは healthy
Through it all, the world is healthy,
おきをたしかにぬるまゆだんし
Keep your wits about you, lukewarm boy!
Uh... wow!
もうちょっとでスキマ埋まるのに な
Even though the gap is almost filled...
（埋まるのに）
(Almost filled...)
どうやってもうまく行かね
No matter what I do, it doesn't work out.
ああ、もう時間が足りない！
Ah, there's just not enough time!
座る 座る (oh) sit down please
Sit, sit, (oh) sit down please
フィードバックに体預けて
Surrendering my body to the feedback,
巡り巡る (oh) turn it around
Round and round, (oh) turn it around
うなりをあげて、モーター状態
Making it roar, we're in motor mode!
踊る 踊る (oh) dancin' night
Dance, dance, (oh) dancin' night
マッシュアップでもれなくアガる 声を
Mashing it up, we'll definitely get hyped! Raise your...
あげて (oh) singin' now
...voice! (oh) singin' now
あの子みたいなひとになりたい
I want to be like that girl...
座る 座る sit down please
Sit, sit, sit down please
(up side down a b a b b a b a a b a b)
巡る 巡る turn it around
Round and round, turn it around
(l r l r stop & dash &)
踊る 踊る dancin' night
Dance, dance, dancin' night
(up side down a b a b b a b a a b a b)
声をあげて singin' now
Raise your voice, singin' now
(l r l r stop & dash &)
あの子みたいなひとになりたい
I want to be like that girl...
Whoa!
I win!
うう、クソ...
Ugh, darn it...
A coin!
Yay!
ほら、ほら、ほら。
Here, here, here.
わあ、何？
Whoa, what?
Go to the next stage.
But, be careful.
次のゲームマスターは僕のようにはいかないぞ。
The next Game Master won't be as easy on you as I was.
No easy.
ええ？大丈夫だよ！ビジューだから！
Eh? I'll be fine! Because I'm Bijou!
Oh, okay.
うん！ありがとう先輩！
Yep! Thank you, Senpai!
じゃあ、バイバイ！
Well, bye-bye!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
わああ！
Whoaaa!
わあ！
Whoa!
Now then... Where to next, I wonder?
We've been waiting for you, Bijou.
Wow.
[Title: IRyS, Ninomae Ina'nis Joins the Battle! Driving Battle]
Huh? IRyS? Ina?
I'm assuming this is what you're looking for, right?
Yes, yes! I need that! I need that! Yes! Give me, give me, I need that coin, give me!
We won't just hand it over. Uh-uh.
You'll have to race us for it.
Ah? Yes.
No, give it, give it, where are you putting that? I'm putting that back in my pocket.
If you want it, you have to beat us. Are you ready to battle?
Fine! I'll be cool, watch this. Oh, hey, I will always win!
Ha!
No one can dull my shine tonight
No one can dull my shine
Hi!
Save me, I think I'm freezing up, so cold inside
舞台は quiet room ふたり
The stage is a quiet room for two
Save me, I need a guiding touch in these dark times
恋人たちのシーン
A scene of lovers
Inside the maze of your heart, I'm the soul that strays
That's right!
But baby look at me, you're not blind
Oh, can't you see that I can be refined
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time
To be your diamond girlfriend
Overheating love machine
burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way
so precious girlfriend, go, go, go!
Overheating love machine
burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
on the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul, break it all, break it all, break it all!
The diamond girlfriend!
しとやかなキャラ豹変
Transforming from a graceful character,
ビートまとい まき散らすのは
wearing a beat, scattering around
ブリンブリンの sparkle だ
a blinding sparkle.
Just heat it and wheel it, make the sword ばっちり
Just heat it and wheel it, make the sword spot on,
まぶしさで目が眩む gem
a gem that blinds your eyes with its radiance.
Trust me, your weary eyes betray what you've tried to hide
言葉無しで伝わり
Communicating without words
Trust me, I'll never shy away from your dark side
空気が変わるフェイズ
The phase where the atmosphere changes
Under the pressure and fire, see these ashes reborn...
Your rebirth!
Let me show you who I really am
Oh, yeah!
In the name of love, I'll be a gem.
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time
to be your diamond girlfriend!
Overheating love machine
burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
let them light the way
so precious girlfriend, go, go, go!
Overheating love machine
burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
on the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul
break it all, break it all, break it all!
No one can dull my shine tonight
no one can dull my shine
no one can dull my shine.
Now C is your atomic symbol
ぐるぐる回せ真っ赤っ赤になるまで wimble
Spin it round and round until it turns bright red, wimble
愛が足りないとか闇が深いほど
The less love there is or the deeper the darkness,
価値ふえる gem 扱う I'm a jeweler
the more value a gem gains, treating it like I'm a jeweler.
さあ踊りなさい!
Come on, dance!
Shine on, shine bright
light my flame
until it all melts away...
Hey! Hey!
Are you ready?
Overheating love machine
burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me
let them light the way
so precious girlfriend, go, go, go!
Overheating love machine
burning hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
on the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul
break it all, break it all, break it all!
No one can dull my shine tonight
no one can dull my shine
no one can dull my shine.
Yeah, we did it! Woohoo! Woohoo!
Are you guys okay?
Yeah! / No!
Did I hit you too hard?
My gem! / Get it!
Yeah! Yes! I got the coin!
I'm the winner! I win!
Uh, wait, what is that?
Oh, look, a portal!
Portal?
Oh, a portal.
By the way, where did the coin come from, IRyS?
Uh... um... it...
Don't worry about it!
It came from my cleavage pocket!
Ah! Portal! Bye! / Goodbye!
Ah! The world is spinning! Whoa!
Ugh... Oh... dizzy...
Huh?
Is this a puzzle stage?
Hey! I'm ready for my next challenge now! Hey, come out! Hey!
は？
Huh?
There's no game master this time?
え？
Eh?
Well, I guess I could use a break or something.
Maybe I'll dance and sing by myself, you know, as a refresher.
Yeah, so I'll be ready for the next challenge.
This is a puzzle stage, so it does remind me of a certain song.
Hey! Everyone over there, you wanna hear it too, right?
Yeah?
Okay, they didn't say anything, I'm just talking to myself.
Well, all right then.
Let's dance Tetris!
どうしてすぐ知ってしまうのか
Why do they always know right away?
共振で苦しんでし罵倒
So annoying to resonate and just curse it out!
q.更新で降る隕石抹消可？ 悪くない
Q: Can refreshing remove the falling meteors? That's okay
興味 ねえ 救い 派手 感動
Indifferent to the self-satisfaction of redemption
常備 ねえ 薬 食べ bad
No stock of terrible-tasting medicine so bad
q.超酷えフル見た目暗号化？ 金による
Q: Super cool appearance but all just gibberish? So give me your money
常識 ねえ 狂いっぱ で 乱闘
Endless chaotic brawls with no sense
放置 ゲー する 陰キャ で バンド
Lonely characters in an idle game for a band
q.送信で苦しい ダメ cancel は？ 草生える
Q: Struggling to communicate so can't revoke the "cancel"? That cracks me up
どうして すぐ 見 てしまう の
Why do they always read instantly?
どうして すぐ 言っ てしまう の
Why do they always reply frankly?
どうして すぐ 壊れちゃう かな
Why does my fragile heart fall apart so easily?
近未来 しか 勝たん
The near future is the way to go
ショッピングモール の 現代 コンピュー
Shopping mall's modern computers
小窓 タブ か 加担
The small window serves as an accomplice to death
モンティ ホール の 経費 で ピンボール
Use the Monty Hall problem's budget to create a pinball game
オイルマッサージ 100 分 コース 足湯 付き
An 100-minute hydraulic massage with a foot bath
柚子 を 添えて
Add yuzu as well
テテ テテトテト テテ テテ トリス
Te-te-te-teto, teto, te-te-te-tetris
どうして こんな 目 に に に
Why did it turn out like this?
興味がないこと本気じゃないもの全部後回しで
Everything I'm not interested in gets delayed because I don't take it seriously
知ってることは知らんぷり私は終わってる
I understand something but pretend to know nothing; I'm beyond help after all
恥ずかしい過去知ってるやつらの記憶消させて
Delete all memories of those who know my awkward past
迷惑かけてごめんってばねえ誰か助けて
I've said that I'm really sorry for causing trouble, so anyone here to give me a hand?
妄信 で すぐ 惹かれちゃう の
Got hooked immediately due to blind trust
狂信 で すぐ 引かれちゃう の
Got trapped from then on due to blind obedience
知り たくない 知り たくない 知り たくない
I don't want to know, I don't want to know, I don't want to know
もう 見 ねえ すぐ 引かれ sad
Can't bear to see and quickly falling into sadness
常勤 で 狂い たて mad
Full-time industry expert about complete madness
生きたくない いきたくない いきたくない
I don't want to go, I don't want to go, I don't want to go
ばーいばい
Bye-bye!
臨時 休業 洗濯 ボール
Temporary closure and detergent pods
ナイチンゲール の 配信 ゲーム
Nightingale's live streaming
名刺 交換 の 名シーン
Famous scene of exchanging business cards
借金 ボウル で チンチロ ハイボール
Using borrowed money cobbled together to join the cee-lo highball game
温泉旅行 3 泊 4 日 食事 付き
Three-day hot spring trip with four nights' stay and all meals included
早く 行きて え
I really want to go soon
テテ テテトテト テテ テテ トリス
Te-te-te-teto, teto, te-te-te-tetris
共感 性 羞恥 ち ち
I feel embarrassed about this but cannot help
鬱とか躁とか忙しくてねむれないわ今日も
Too busy with depression and restlessness today to find a peaceful sleep
誰か早く殴って気絶させてくれよ
Who can come quickly and knock me into a deep sleep with a punch?
人生 キャンセル キャンセル 界隈
Feeling a bit hazy and uneasy about the circle of people...
ぼんやりとした不安
...who are giving up on life and just lying flat
私のせい私が悪いよそうだよ
The mistake is mine, it's all my fault i'm like this
興味が出ても本気でやっても全部空回りで
Even if I become interested and give it my all, it still feels like an empty effort
知らないくせに嘘つき私は終わってる
Knowing nothing, yet insisting on lying, I think I'm doomed too
恥ずかしい過去知ってるやつらの記憶消させて
Delete all memories of those who know my awkward past
迷惑かけてごめんってばねえ誰か助けて
I've said that I'm really sorry for causing trouble, so anyone here to give me a hand?
迷惑かけてごめんってばねえ誰か
I've said that I'm really sorry for causing trouble, so anyone...
許して
...forgive me!
Whoa, ah!
Oh my, dizzy, dizzy!
Oh, that scared me!
I don't know, this game's bugged, man! Hey, someone report these bugs, dang it!
Cubes start popping out and everything starts...
Ooh, who designed this? I need to meet the devs. Hey, devs!
Schemes malfunction...
But, I don't have time for that! I gotta find the coins!
Ah!
え？
Eh?
Oh, I guess that's my cue to leave.
Okay, next stage, let's charge up!
Helicopter! Helicopter!
Ah! Oh!
I gotta work on that landing...
Oooh!
え？
Eh?
Oh, wow, what a cute stage!
かわいい！
So cute!
Oh, ho ho ho ho ho!
Huh?
どうもどうも、待ってましたよ、ビブ！
Well, well. I've been waiting for you, Biboo!
白上フブキ参戦！ クレーンゲームバトル
[Screen] Shirakami Fubuki Joins the Battle! Crane Game Battle
Fubuki's here, buddy!
ビブ、これが欲しいんだよね？
Biboo, you want this, don't you?
欲しい！欲しい！
I want it! I want it!
ならば白上と勝負だ！
Then you'll have to face me, Shirakami!
白上のクレーンゲームから果たして逃げられるかな？
I wonder if you can escape from Shirakami's crane game!
え？
Eh?
Okay, then! 負けないよ！
Okay, then! I won't lose!
うむ！
Indeed!
LONELY ROLLING STAR
[Screen] LONELY ROLLING STAR
陽だまり
Laying in the sun...
サンサン
...brilliantly bright,
ココロは
my heart...
晴れ模様
...is sunny.
ふたつの
Those two...
瞳は
...eyes...
ヒマワリ
...are like sunflower...
の種のよう
...seeds.
語らい
A lover's chat,
重なり
piling up,
カタマリ
forming a clump,
絡まり
and getting entangled.
一緒に
Being...
いること
...together...
絶対
...is absolutely...
必然
...inevitable.
でもあなた 大事な
But you are drawing...
夢を描く
...your important dream.
終わるまでは
Until it's finished,
ずっとそう
I'll be right...
ここで待っている
...here waiting for you.
you're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star,
立ち止まらないでね
so don't stop standing still, okay?
you're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star,
さぁ前を向いて行こう
so face forward and let's keep going!
星空
A starry sky,
a starry sky,
キラキラ
sparkling,
コンペイ
like confetti,
トウのよう
waiting to celebrate.
甘くて
Sweet...
切ない
...and painful...
思いが
...thoughts...
募るの
...are growing.
抱きしめた思いは
The thoughts I've embraced...
夜空を舞い
...roil and dance in the night sky.
急降下して
They dive down rapidly...
あなたのもとへ
...to be by your side...
ただ届くから
...and reach you.
ただ配るから
Just giving them out!
you're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star,
あきらめないでよね
don't ever give up, okay?
you're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star,
たまには電話して
don't forget to call me sometimes.
you're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star,
会いたいよ今すぐ
I want to see you right now.
you're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star,
はぁ タメイキがひとつ
Ah, with a single sigh...
こぼれる
...that spills over.
lonely rolling, lonely rolling
lonely rolling, lonely rolling star
lonely rolling, lonely rolling, lonely rolling star
来月また あの場所で
Next month, at that place...
待ち合わせしようか
...shall we meet up again?
you're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star,
立ち止まらないでね
so don't stop standing still, okay?
you're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star,
思い出してよね
remember me, okay?
you're lonely rolling star
You're a lonely rolling star,
待ってられないよね
I can't keep on waiting, you know!
...よね
...right?
Lonely Rolling Star
さあ...
Come on...
前を向いて
...look straight ahead...
行こう
...and let's go!
いやー！
Yeah!
I won! I won! Yeeees!
あれは使っちゃダメだよ、ビブ！
Hey, you shouldn't use that, Biboo!
あはは、ボコボコにされてるよ！
Ahaha, I got beaten up!
負けたよ！
I lost!
コインだ、いえーい！
A coin! Yay!
I'm the winner!
可愛いから許して！
I'm cute, so forgive me!
しょうがない、許す！可愛いからね！
Oh well, I forgive you since you're cute!
じゃあ、次の世界へビブ！あ、めくるがいい！
Then on to the next world, Biboo! Go on, flip it!
OK！ジャンプお願い！
OK! Jump, please!
はい、行くよ！Let's go、かぎー！
Here we go! Let's go, key!
There, I think we're doing great now, aren't we?
Who's next, huh? I'm ready for my next challenge!
ワフワフ！
Awoo!
待っていたぞ、ビブ！
I've been waiting for you, Biboo!
Todoroki Hajime Joins the Battle! / Rhythm Dance Battle
はじめ？！ワッツ？！
Hajime?! What?!
これが欲しければ、自分と勝負だ！
If you want this, you have to duel me!
My coin! Whaaa...
はじめのダンスについて来られるかな？
Can you keep up with Hajime's dance?
Eh? Dance? Hmph!
Okay! Let's dance together!
いやー！いやー！
Yeah! Yeah!
みんなー！ チルノのさんすう教室はじまるよー！
Everyone! Cirno's Math Class is starting!
あたいみたいな天才目指して、がんばっていってね！
Aim to be a genius like me, and do your best!
キラキラ ダイヤモンド 輝く星のように
Sparkling diamond, like a shining star,
栄光 志望校 なんとかして入ろう
by any means, let's get into our dream school.
天才 秀才 トップ目指して GO GO!!
Genius, prodigy, aim for the top, GO GO!!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
ちょ、ちが、バカじゃないもん！
Wh-What? I am not an idiot!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
バカっていうほうがバカなのよ！
The one who says 'idiot' is the idiot!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
なによ、うるさいわね！このバカ！
What did you say? Shut up, you idiot!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
紅魔館からバスが出て 始めに三人乗りました
A bus departs from Scarlet Devil Mansion, with three passengers at start.
白玉楼で一人降りて 半人だけ乗りました
One gets off at Hakugyokurou, and half a person boards.
八雲さんちで二人降りて 結局乗客合計何人だ？
Two get off at Yakumo's place, how many passengers are left in total?
答えは 答えは なぜならなぜならそれは
The answer is... The answer is... Because, because, that's because...
幻想郷にバス無い
There are no buses in Gensokyo!
山落ち意味など無いわ キャラクター立てばいいのよ
Climax or punchline don't matter, as long as the character stands out!
元気があればなんでも
As long as you have energy, anything goes!
1・2・9!!
1, 2, 9!!
くるくる時計の針 ぐるぐる頭まわる
The hands of the clock spin round, making my head spin round.
だってつぶら目玉 二つしかないのに
After all, I only have two round eyes,
三本の針なんて ちんぷんかんぷん
So three hands on a clock make no sense to me!
次々問題出る まだまだ授業続く
Problems keep popping up, the class goes on and on.
凍る部屋の中 ひんやりした温度も時間も気にせず ゆっくりしていってね！
Inside the frozen room, oblivious to the chilly temperature and time, take it easy!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
だからバカって言わないでって言ってるでしょ！
I told you, stop calling me an idiot!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
いい加減にしないとお怒りするわよ！
Stop it already, or I'm going to get mad!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
そして粉々になって死ねばいいのよ！
And then you should just shatter into pieces and die!
バーカバーカ バーカバーカ
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
霊夢んとこの百万円の 壺を誰かが割っちゃった
Someone broke Reimu's one-million yen vase!
永遠亭のえーりんが 弁償に来ましたよ
Eirin from Eientei came to pay compensation.
知らんぷりのイタズラてゐ 結局賠償金額いくら？
Tewi plays dumb and plays pranks. So, how much is the compensation in the end?
答えは 答えは なぜならなぜならそれは
The answer is... The answer is... Because, because, that's because...
そんな壺あるわけない
There's no way she has a vase like that!
常識超えたところに 世界の真理がある
Beyond common sense is where the truth of the world lies,
秘密の数字目指して
aiming for the secret number,
1・2・9!!
1, 2, 9!!
ヘラヘラニヤけながら
Grinning and smirking foolishly,
ゲラゲラ笑いながら
Laughing and chuckling out loud,
うっざー！
So annoying!
因幡ウサギ 可愛げもないのに 新参の厨どもは ホイホイホイ
Even though that Inaba rabbit isn't cute, the newbies follow her blindly!
再生百万回 もれなく愚民なんて
One million views, and every single one is a fool.
どういうことなのよ どちらかって言うならさあ
What is the meaning of this? If anything...
サーバー管理もお疲れさんってとこね
we should thank them for managing the servers!
「わかった！ アタイがあまりにも天才だから嫉妬してるんでしょ」
"I get it! You're just jealous because I'm such a genius!"
「ほんと、しょうがないわね」
"Honestly, you're hopeless."
「せっかく近々アタイの天才の秘訣をちょっとだけ教えてあげてもいいわよ」
"But since I'm generous, maybe I'll teach you a bit of my genius secret soon!"
あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの 兵を
My, my, my, my, my, my, my, my... soldiers!
集めて 集めて 集めて 集めて 束ねても
Even if I gather, gather, gather, gather, and unite them...
あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの 豆腐な
My, my, my, my, my, my... tofu-like...
頭に 頭に 頭に 頭に かなわない
brain still can't compare!
あつめち あつめち あつめち あつめち 食べたら
If I gather, gather, gather, gather and eat them...
赤子の 赤子の 赤子の 赤子の 手をひねる
it's as easy as twisting a baby's arm!
あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの あたいの 完璧
My, my, my, my, my, my... perfect!
いわゆる いわゆる いわゆる いわゆる パーフェクト
The so-called, so-called, so-called... perfect!
ひゃくおくちょうまんバッチリ！
A hundred billion trillion percent spot on!
山落ち意味など無いわ キャラクター立てばいいのよ
There's no need for a climax, as long as the character stands out.
元気があればなんでも なんでも 1 2 9!
If you have energy, anything, anything is... 1, 2, 9!
くるくる時計の針
Round and round go the clock hands...
くるくる頭まわる
round and round my head spins.
だってつぶら目玉二つしかないのに
Since I only have two round eyes...
三本の針なんてちんぷんかん
three clock hands are completely gibberish!
氷結問題出る
The freezing question comes up...
まだまだ授業続く
the class continues on and on.
凍る部屋の中ひんやりした温度も時間も気にせずゆっくりしていってね！
In the freezing room, without caring about the chilly temperature or the time, take it easy!
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot!
もうバカでいいわよ！しるか！
Fine, I'll be an idiot! Who cares!
バーカ バーカ
Idiot, idiot!
アタイのダンスについて来られるなんて なかなかやるな！
To be able to keep up with my dance, you're pretty good!
よし、コインをやろう。
Alright, I'll give you a coin.
はっ！
Ha!
Yay! I got a coin!
Thank you, Hajime! Thank you for dancing with me! めっちゃ楽しかった！
Thank you, Hajime! Thank you for dancing with me! It was so much fun!
楽しかった！ / ありがとう！
It was fun! / Thank you!
Thank you.
So, I must go. / Oh, okay.
Bye-bye! / Bye-bye!
Go!
おお！
Oh!
Oh, we're here already. Okay. Oh, I see.
Woah, what's next? And the rest is... I can count.
One, two... Two challenges left, I think, for two coins.
は！？
Huh!?
待っていたぞ！
We have been waiting for you!
ビブー！
Biboo!
天音かなた ラプラス・ダークネス 参戦！ ゾンビ殲滅戦
Amane Kanata, La+ Darknesss Joins the Battle! Zombie Elimination
え！？ かなた先輩！？ ラプラス！？ 何してるの、ここで？
Eh!? Kanata-senpai!? La+!? What are you doing here?
これ欲しければ... / 我々と勝負だ！
If you want this... / Fight with us!
私のコイン！ / 勝負だ！
My coin! / It's a duel!
迫り来るゾンビを...
Defeating all the...
全部倒すことが... / できるかな！？
approaching zombies... / can you do it!?
ああ、じゃあ、外しはしない！
Well, then, I won't miss!
Make It Out Alive
Run away, run away, run away / You don't know who to run from
Nowhere to go, nowhere to go, nowhere to go / No road is left to run on
I was born, I was born with horns / Demons couldn't shake me up
Bring it on, bring it on, bring it on / 'Cause we haven't had enough
Won't give up the fight
Make it out alive / Set this world on fire now
Woah, woah / Don't give up, it's gonna be alright
'Cause I won't let you burn out / Woah, woah
We gotta make it out alive
tonight, tonight, tonight / I'm screaming on the inside
I was trying to hide, trying to hide, trying to hide
not ready for this ride
gotta face, gotta face the unknown
it's the only way to live
I'm ready to go, ready to go, ready to go
somewhere I've never been
won't give up the fight
make it out alive
set this world on fire now / woah, woah
don't give up
it's gonna be alright / 'cause I won't let you burn out
woah, woah / we gotta make it out alive
won't let you burn out
make it out alive
set this world on fire now / woah, woah
don't give up
it's gonna be alright / 'cause I won't let you burn out
woah, woah
won't let you burn out
we're gonna make it out alive
make it out, make it out!
全部倒すなんてすっげーじゃん！
Clearing them all, that's amazing!
あっ、終わった？勝利！
Ah, is it over? Victory!
よし！コインをやろう！
Alright! Let's toss a coin!
おっ、コイン！やったー！うわああ！
Oh, a coin! Yay! Whoa!
みんな、ありがとうね。
Thanks, everyone.
おい、ハッピーバースデー！
Hey, happy birthday!
あっ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
You are winning! Okay!
じゃあ、さようならー！
Well, goodbye!
くそっ！何でできない…
Dammit! Why can't we do it...
Nice landing! Yeah!
Huh?
Oh, it's the first stage.
Maybe this is like a... progress check sort of thing?
Let's see. Let's see where I'm at, huh?
Oh! I'm missing one more coin!
But where could it be?
Is anyone here to give me another game or something?
Hello? Hello?
Maybe this is like the safe zone where I can like take a break and recover.
That's a good idea! You know...
I'm feeling kind of tired, and all the songs have been so baby intense!
Let's... let's take a break. I'll just take a nap.
I'll be... I'll wake up. I'll just...
I'll just... give me like 5 minutes, okay? Just... just 5 minutes.
Oyasumi, world...
Goodnight, world...
You know, oyasumi. See ya, see ya.
You know, goodnight. See ya, see ya.
[Title: Flow / Lyrics: Kathryn Cwynar, Natsuko Ishikawa / Music: Masayoshi Soken]
Well come and well met, my brave little spark
How long you've wandered, burned bright as a star
Oh, I...
Oh, I have awaited you patiently all this time
Past every fate
Now sing with me once more, share of your life
Far greater than memory, its loss and love words cannot hold
Boundless the tale overflows
And carries your light out to sea
Remember the rain, near and far beloved
Each drop a blessing from heavens above
And how as time flowed on those waters became one
Streams, rivers and lakes
Reaching for the horizon and far beyond
They carry onward however changed
with each brief reflection, by setting sun
By storm's wake
Til welcomed home to gentle sea
Sinking deeper and deeper in calm embrace
Loving tides sweep in and bear you down
Should you meet a soul rising surface-ways
With your unbeating heart, wish them well
Deep, dark, far away,
I have heard your voice, weighed your every choice
Now our hands join round the meaning you sought
I'll catch your tears, quench your fears
with joy til you near the shore
Where in time, all shall as hope be reborn, ah
Hush, love, close your eyes, and in sleep abide
As sun's distant light, echoes down to dreams below
Know you will wake, on winds rise again
For this journey's end is but one step forward to tomorrow
What a good dream!
All right, let's check our progress then.
Hmm, we're still missing one coin.
Where could it be?
Again!
What's happening?!
What the bleep?!
I've been waiting for you, Bijou.
Fake Biboo Joins the Battle!
Yo- You're...
I'm you.
Me?
You mean my last opponent is... me?
Exactly.
Me...
You.
Your biggest enemy.
Your biggest obstacle.
Yourself.
No...
You've done well at making it this far, Bijou.
But I don't intend to hold back.
Then... I won't either!
This stage is too important for me to give up now!
Weight of the World / 壊レタ世界ノ歌
Weight of the World / Broken World's Song
I feel like I'm losing hope
In my body and my soul
And the sky,
it looks so ominous
And as time comes to a halt
Silence starts to overflow
My cries
are inconspicuous
Tell me, God,
are you punishing me?
Is this the price I'm paying
for my past mistakes?
This
is my redemption song
I need you more than ever right now
Can you hear me now?
Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
I wish that someway, somehow
That I could save every one of us
But the truth is that I'm only one girl
Maybe if I keep believing
My dreams will come to life
Come to life
溢れる緑
Greenery overflows...
零れる命
...wasted lives.
風は今も遠く
Even now, the wind is far away.
剥がれる錆びと
The peeling rust and...
蠢く刃
...the writhing blade...
死が潜む森に
...in the forest where death lurks.
これが僕の
This is my...
呪い
...curse.
約束殺す
The pain that...
痛みが
...kills my promise...
キミの
...your...
願い
...wish...
最後の夢を捨てて
...discarding my final dream.
贖いだけど
Though it is redemption,
そう僕らは今
and so, we right now,
ああ 無価値でも叫ぶ
ah, even if it's worthless, we cry out...
この汚れた世界の愛
...the love of this filthy world.
そう僕らは今
And so, we right now,
ああ 無意味でも願う
ah, even if it's meaningless, we hope...
ただキミとの時間を
...only for my time with you.
溺れた意識は
Our drowning consciousness...
優しいまま
...remains gentle...
消えて
...as it fades away.
'Cause we're gonna shout it loud
Even if our words seem meaningless
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world
そう僕らは今
So we are now...
ああ無意味でも願う
Ah, even if it's meaningless, I pray
ただ君との未来を
Just for a future with you
Still, we're gonna shout it loud /
そう僕らは今
So we are now...
Even if our words seem meaningless /
ああ無価値でも叫ぶ
Ah, even if worthless, I will shout
It's like I'm carrying the weight of the world /
あの壊レタ世界ノ歌
That song of a broken world
I hope that someway, somehow /
そう僕らは今
So we are now...
That I could save every one of us /
ああ無意味でも願う
Ah, even if meaningless, I pray
But the truth is that I'm only one girl /
ただ君との時間を
Just for our time together
Maybe if I keep believing /
祈りが赦しを
Even if our prayers do not bring forgiveness
My dreams will come to life /
得られずとも
...or redemption
僕は
I am...
Mm, impressive.
Yes! The coin!
Oh, you're still alive. Oh.
You who have defeated all the game masters shall be rewarded.
Huh? What, what is this?
Now, show this to everyone.
Yeah! Hey, thanks! But, um...
There can only be one!
Oh, oh, I'm here! Oh, oh, oh...
Hello, everyone! We have made it to the final stage!
You didn't think I collected all those coins and played all those games for nothing, did you?
No, because I'm cashing it in!
With all of these coins we have unlocked...
my new original song!
And guess what? The video is gonna come out right after this!
Good job, everyone!
And I'm gonna perform it to you...
right now!
Are you ready? Let's go out with a bang!
Rock in!
Biboo's here to play!
Yeah, uh-huh!
Uh-uh!
Let's go!
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in
(I was all in)
What if that was me soaring straight to the top?
Let's take a chance, game on, and shoot my shot!
Log in, get good, you mad? Let's cook!
Talk beep, get hit, clean sweep!
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo Biboo
Come and test your luck
Yeah, we comin' in clutch, Biboo Biboo
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, Biboo Biboo
Come and help me fight
Get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
Rock in!
Bubu ba bububu ba, bubu ba bubu
Bubu ba bam bam ba, bubu ba bubu
Bubu ba baba ba, bububu bububu bububu ba
Level up, we go onwards
Aiming for another win
A diamond in the rough, it's kinda tough
You gotta keep on rollin'
(Gotta keep on rollin')
The grind goes on and on, no breaks
Seal the cracks with a few bandaids
I'll try over and over and over again
Just one more round, please?
Now you know what's up, hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo, Biboo
Come and test your luck, yeah, we're comin' in clutch, Biboo, Biboo
Skipping stone in flight, take 'em out one-shot, Biboo, Biboo
Come and help me fight, get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss. Rock in!
Lost in this game, I feel the strain
But I'm pulled back up by your gravity
Your gravity
I see the shape, I feel the space
It's set in stone, carve it into me
I just wanna be Biboo
Now you know what's up, hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo, Biboo
Come and test your luck, yeah, we're comin' in clutch, Biboo, Biboo
Skipping stone in flight, take 'em out one-shot, Biboo, Biboo
Better hit quicksave 'cause Biboo's here to play
Now you know what's up, hit 'em with a one-two-three, Biboo, Biboo
Come and test your luck, yeah, we're comin' in clutch, Biboo, Biboo
Skipping stone in flight, take 'em out one-shot, Biboo, Biboo
Come and help me fight, get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss. Rock in!
Biboo, Biboo!
Huh?
Hello?
Um, I'm still here.
Uh, ready to get teleported back to my world... any... anytime now.
Mom!
Pick me up!
I'm scared!
Hey!
This wasn't part of the deal!
No, wait. What are you doing?
No!
No! No! No!
Hey, listen to my song at least!
Okay, my song is coming on, listen to it!
Rock in!
Go! Go!
Aaaah!